That you want to buy a particular term plan
and want to understand its variants, then
in our today's video we will talk about term plans
and many factors and many factors related to it
and also talk about what the different
options that you have to choose here
mean for you, if
you choose one option then its
plan's meaning changes
for you, so watch this video completely so
that you get all the information related to term plan
and you can choose the right option for yourself,
before we start the video,
I am Mamta Khanna, Certified
Financial Planner and you are watching
West Indies India YouTube channel, your one
stop destination, so better right pension
revise, so let's do it,
Super Protector Life Friends of ICICI Prudential,
thirdly this is a term plan of
ICICI Prudential
and here you get four bed
and variants, here there is Life Plus, Life
and Help and All in One, four options are
given to you and what do they mean for you,
let's talk now  Yes, here first of all let's
talk about the life option.
In the life option, you are given the option of permanent
disability live coverage and also the
option of terminal illness.
So here you get three types of coverage.
If you are diagnosed with a terminal illness, then
in that case the sum assured is given to you. In
case of any unfortunate
event, all the money is given to your nominee.
And if you suffer from any permanent disability, then
in that case
your premium is paid here and
your policy continues. So this is your life
option where you are getting pure live coverage.
Now let's talk about the coverage of the
live plus option.
Here all the benefits are same as in the
life option, but here you get
accidental cover extra. In case of
accidental death, the sum assured of
accidental death coverage is
added to the original sum assured.
Suppose your life coverage is
of ₹1 and you have taken an accidental rider of
₹2500000.  In case of accidental death
normally Rs. 12500000 is given above.
Now let's talk about Life in Health Option. Here
all the variants of Torch Light Option
are available along with this you can purchase Excel Nested Critical
Illness Benefit Rider here.
In this rider, the patient and critical
illness are covered
and if any critical illness is
diagnosed to you, then in that case whatever is the
remaining time of the rider is given to you
and you can get your treatment done with that money
or you can do whatever you think is appropriate at that time with
that money. It is
not like that you will get the entire
money gradually, as soon as the diagnosis is done and
you submit the papers, then
this cover is given to you there. Now the first option is
All in One Option where you get the
return of critical illness along with
Accidental Rider and the rest of the
variants of Life Option are given to the Life Option.
If we talk about critical illness, then there are many
critical options here.  There are several illnesses like
cancer of the liver,
a specific acidity, your heart and heart-
related diseases, major organ benefit. It is
important to note here that there are
options like end stage, short end stage liver failure, kidney failure and such,
which you should carefully consider
before purchasing any power. Now let's talk about
this, but suppose someone has a disease, then
what options are given to you in that case. So
here are the claim
options as to how you want to give the money to your nominee.
If you want them to be
paid in a lump sum, then that
option is available. If you want,
you can give them an income option. If you
feel that your nominee
cannot handle this money and it can be
misused, then you
can give them income benefit, in which ten percent of your
time will be
given to them every year. If the
capacity of one crore is more, then ten
percent of that will be given to them every year.  It will be given for 10 years,
it is converted into monthly installments,
but 80 percent will be
given to them every month. The third option for your time saver is
long term and income, some
money will be given to them for a long time and the remaining
money will be used to make monthly installments
at 80 percent and this
money will be given to them for 10 years, but there is no
provision for giving it after 10 years.
If you want them to
get money according to the increase in income, then this
income will be increased every year at 10 percent,
so these are the four options when it comes to death benefit. There are
patient options which you have to choose
when you purchase the policy.
Apart from this, the beneficiary can get his
monthly income converted into lump sum at any time,
but
this option can be taken at a discount of 4%, so
now you can have different appointments.
Suppose you are unmarried now and you live for some time
on merit.  In which you can increase your term and
if you get married
then at that time you
can increase your term up to 50% of the original term.
Suppose you have a cover of Rs 1 crore then
you can increase it to Rs 1.5 crore. On that basis
you can increase your term up to 25%
and similarly
you can increase it by 25% on the basis of second tile also
but here there
is also an option of maximum and additional tax benefit that you cannot add more than ₹5000000
and you cannot add more than Rs 25 lakh on both the berths also,
so this is the lightest protection plan of which you
can add. Apart from this, if we talk about
eligibility that when you purchase from the order then
you are given three options
here, one is
Google Pay, that is, if
you do
not want to go through the hassle of paying the entire premium again and again every year then you
can buy your coverage by paying just a single premium and here you have to pay the
premium only once. Second  The option is
regular payment. Now, for whatever live
coverage you have, for whatever period you have taken your plan, the
maximum here is nine years
- whatever is your current age - you
can also take your time and here
you will have to pay the premium for the same number of years as your policy term. If you
talk about the limit, then in this case,
you have taken the policy for years and here you
want to pay your premium in the limit time mentioned 5 years, 7 years or 10 years, then
you can choose that option also, but
here if we suggest you, then the
regular payment option
is the best or if you want to make a single payment, then
it is much better because through that
you have to pay less premium. Regularly, the
minimum premium here is Rs.24
and
if you purchase ADB or Accidental Death
Benefit cover, then
you will have to purchase a minimum of ₹1, hence
you
can take your Accidental Death Benefit cover equal to the time you have taken and
a Critical Illness  The minimum term is Rs 1 lakh
and the maximum is given to you according to the underwriting policy. The
minimum term
here is the minimum premium and the
maximum term is unlimited. You
can take any amount of term but the subject is
underwriting. You
can take any premium. You can pay a single premium, you can pay it
annually, you
can pay it half yearly or
you can also choose a minister. Now let's talk
about some examples.
Priya, who is a 32-year-old
marketing consultant, if she
took a base plan of Rs 1 crore and also
took a critical illness cover of Rs 25,00,000, then
her policy is for 30 years and she
will pay Rs 18,000 on a regular premium. So, she is
interested in
purchasing a policy for 32 years and
she is paying her regular premium. At the
age of 40, she suffers a critical illness.
In that case,  ₹2500000 are
given to them here and the rest of the cover of
their child or ₹2500000 and
their premium is also decreased proportionately.
If later due to any reason
Priya dies unfortunately, then
₹2500000 will be given to her nominee.
This electrician number one
talks about each other's name
that Anil bought a car worth Rs 1.5 crore
and he was paying its annual premium of
around Rs 22,000. On Anil's death,
his family will be given a monthly income of
Rs 1 lakh 25 thousand. There was an income of 14
years.